[music]
>> What's up, faithful? Welcome back to the
saloon presented by Cisco. I'm your
49ers team reporter, Briana Janel,
sitting down with our digital editor,
Brooke Evans, as we recap everything
from the 2026 NFL Draft. Brooke, I want
to hear your thoughts coming out of this
weekend. I mean, we started with six
picks, ended up with eight. How are you
feeling? I think, all around, it was a
success. I [music] mean, the two
favorite words that are coming out of
this draft are consensus and conviction.
Um trust the board mindset definitely
continues, and I think that's awesome to
see the front office is so happy. We
came out with a wide receiver, a running
back, two D-linemen, two O-linemen, a
linebacker, a cornerback, and a pick in
the 2027 draft. So, all good things to
talk about. Another thing that I think I
saw was
we're always going to prioritize best
player available, which is awesome to
see, and I love that the consensus part
about that is across everyone to that
level. Everyone's in agreement on that.
Another thing that I think I see is the
athletic traits plus character is the
priority. He could be the best one on
the board, but he's got to do really
well in those interviews, and John Lynch
harped on how important those are. And
so, it was just really cool, the whole
thing of seeing all the smiling faces.
You got to speak with them. The whole
weekend was a success, for sure. That's
right. Day 3 was a crazy day for the
49ers, because not only did we have our
first pick coming to the building to
meet and greet all of the 49ers staff.
We'll talk a little bit more about him
in this podcast, but we also chatted
with every single fourth and fifth round
pick we had today. And then, once it was
all wrapped up, we got to hear from
President of Football Operations, John
Lynch, head coach, Kyle Shanahan, and
also some of the scouting team. So, I
had conversations with a ton of people
today. That's why I've got a ton of
notes here. Um so, if I'm looking down,
I'm referencing them, making sure I hit
all the points here. But yeah, so pretty
much Shanahan hopes that all these
draftees make the team. That's going to
be really hard, given the very
successful free agency that the team had
during the offseason, but that's still
the hope that you have when you are
making these calls to the draftees. Now,
that doesn't mean that they can make the
team perhaps in their second of or third
year after some development, but again,
that's the hope for all the guys that
make this team and the goal for these
drafts. Right. Now, another point I do
want to hit is that another move that
impacted the roster during this draft
was on Day 2, the 49ers traded
linebacker Dee Winters to the Dallas
Cowboys in exchange for pick number 152
that was then again dealt in another
trade. But, John Lynch really thanked
Dee for his contributions to this team
and this locker room. He had a huge and
impactful season last year, and that
goes completely noticed, and we give a
ton of props for Dee for what he's done
here at the organization. However, the
Cowboys have been wanting him for quite
a while. They were actually interested
in Dee during that Osa Odighizuwa trade,
and so they've had their eyes on Dee
Winters. Dee Winters is a Texas native,
and so he goes back to his home state,
and John Lynch said that there's a ton
of opportunity out there for him. So, it
sounds a bit of a win-win for both the
49ers and the Cowboys. Brooke, what were
your thoughts on that?
>> Yeah, I know, I fully agree with that. I
think, you know, John Lynch talking
about how there is so much opportunity
for him is only exciting things. So, I
think that was, you know, it's always so
tough to see people go, but it's almost
like you want to see them be able to
flourish, and hopefully this is going to
be a great environment for him. Exactly.
So, shout out Dee Winters. Thank you for
all you've done for us throughout the
past few years. But, let's just dive
right into this 2026 49ers draft class.
The first pick came in Round 2 at pick
number 33, wide receiver DeJean
Stripling. Brooke, when you were reading
up on him, cuz you had the first article
out on 49ers.com about him, what did you
learn about DeJean and what he brings to
the 49ers organization?
>> Yeah, so a little overview on Stripling,
he's an Ole Miss wide receiver. He
actually has played in five college
seasons, has seen three different
programs between Washington State,
Oklahoma State, and then Ole Miss. And
he's a Hawaiian native, so that's why we
saw that selfie video we got on social
media of him in his Hawaiian lei, and I
think that was really cool to get a
little bit of his personality. But
really, why the 49ers like him, he's
6'2, 207 lb with four and ran a 4.39 in
the 40, which is a really rare combo for
his size and the speed. So, I think that
immediately stood out to them. He's a
complete receiver. So, not just about
speed. They really like that he's a
strong route runner. He's physical after
the catch when he's carrying the ball,
and his blocking ability really stood
out, not only to our front office, but
other people talking about him. So, I
think that obviously obviously made him
someone that was intriguing as a wide
receiver to pick.
Um and they were talking about how he
can kind of step into a Jauan Jennings
style type of role. So, I think those
are all good things, and I think the
biggest takeaway from this is, like I
mentioned, this is a really coveted pick
at 33, and they still took him, even
though people were offering trades. So,
I think that just shows how much they
believe in him and what they saw on the
film. Like Kyle Shanahan said,
everything goes back to the film. Like
John Lynch always says, everything goes
back to the film. Um some quotes they
have on this on him as well.
"There's a lot to love on this kid,"
said Kyle Shanahan. "He's big, he's
strong, plays with tremendous
physicality, legit speed, and to be that
size running a 4.39, that shows on tape.
We love the total package." So, I think,
you know, when you look at our free
agency and we have other wide receivers
that we brought in, it's what
characteristics can set this guy apart,
and the fact that he he has
the physical and
mental traits to be that full package is
huge. What more did you get to learn
about him? That's right. From Hawaii to
the Bay, he had a long journey here, but
he was well rested. He slept on the
plane, and I asked him how he was
feeling, and it was just pure excitement
from him and his family. But, I'll
rewind the tape a little bit to the day
we actually picked him. I spoke to John
Lynch right after the pick, and John
mentioned that he was a gold helmet guy.
And that's the highest honor that the
scouting team gives a prospect during
the draft process, and they only had it
was in the teens. I want to say either
12 or maybe 16, but it was definitely in
the teens of the number of gold helmet
picks that they had in this year's
draft. And for him to be available at
number 33, and for them to pick him, was
an absolute touchdown for this front
office. And so, I was really excited to
hear about his background in the
scouting department. But yeah, it I
asked him, because he mentioned that it
felt surreal when he got the call, and
it didn't feel like reality. So, I asked
him, you know, when did it hit, and when
did you feel that this moment it
actually coming true, and that you were
actually going to be the 49ers newest
wide receiver? And he said it hit him on
the plane when he was
>> on that plane where he has a lot of time
to think.
>> Exactly. When he was landing here in the
Bay Area. So, he again is a Hawaiian
native, and he mentioned that's the home
of the faithful. A ton of people who
live out in Hawaii are huge 49ers fans,
and so he heard from his community, he
heard from his family how amazing the
49ers organization is, and so he was
hyped up from the moment he got the
call. Um Another little tidbit I learned
about him is that he actually trained
with DK Metcalf, who is his friend from
Ole Miss. They played at Ole Miss, not
necessarily, I don't think, at the same
time, but they both are Ole Miss alum,
and so he trained with DK Metcalf,
learned a ton from him about what it
takes to be a receiver in the league. Um
and then, when he came into the building
here, he actually ran into Fred Warner.
And so, not only does he already know
what it takes to compete in this league,
but he also knows what the brotherhood
feels like in this locker room, cuz he
felt it immediately. He mentioned Fred
Warner in my one-on-one with him that I
sat down that will soon be out on the
49ers platforms, but it was really cool
to see how everything is already coming
into the fold for him. And again, you
mentioned it, on his scouting reports,
he's got speed, he's got an insane catch
radius, he's got the willingness to
block, and he can do amazing things
after the catch. Two of Kyle Shanahan's
favorite things in a receiver. So, I
spoke to him right after he got the
call. Let's take a look at it right
here. And with the 49ers first pick in
the 2026 NFL Draft, the 49ers have
selected wide receiver, DeJean
Stripling. DeJean, how are you feeling
right now? What's going through your
mind after hearing your name called by
the San Francisco 49ers? So blessed, so
excited to be here. I'm really grateful
for this opportunity, and I'm just very
excited.
>> Tell us where you are right now, who
you're with, and how you're spending
your draft day. Yeah, back in Hawaii,
at this beach house that we have. I'm
here with just close family, friends
from high school, friends from growing
up, you know. So, just a very chill
vibe. We out here on the beach, you
know, just hanging out and just taking
everything in. Now, what's your message
to the faithful as they are so excited
to welcome you to the Bay? Oh, I'm just
so excited to come here and work and
just for the opportunity and just
contribute however I can and just help
the team win, you know. Congratulations,
DeJean. Enjoy the day.
Thank you. I appreciate you so much.
Now, moving on to the third round, still
in Day 2, pick number 70, defensive
lineman Romello Height. Brooke, when you
were learning about his collegiate
career, what really stood out to you?
So, six college seasons over four
programs, Auburn, USC, Georgia Tech, and
Texas Tech. So, he ended at Texas Tech
and had a breakout final year there, and
that's really what sold them. They had
10 He had 10 sacks and 11 and 1/2
tackles for loss. In his career totals,
had 111 tackles, 27 tackles for loss,
and 16 and 1/2 sacks. So, these are
great numbers to put up. And then, at
the combine, he ranked high amongst all
of the defensive ends. So, really easy
to stand out there, and really what
is such a good thing about him is that
he fits the 49ers D-line identity. He's
got a high motor, extremely relentless
player, and he's versatile. He's an edge
rusher, can drop, and and be in a hybrid
role. Something that Kyle Shanahan said
about him is
quote unquote, "The way he played, the
style he played, is exactly what we
want. Very relentless. We have a playing
with your hair on fire grade,
and he was at the top of it." So, I
think that's really cool to think about
is when they're going through players,
it's who's got their hair on fire,
right? Who's that relentless, that guy
that wants to bring the energy and he
was at the top of that list. So, it was
really cool to see them make that pick
at number 70. I also love hearing the
titles of grades that front office gives
each of these guys. They've got a hair
on fire grade. I remember there was also
like a get off on the ball grade that we
talked about last year, the gold helmet
guys and then this year I was talking
with John Lynch with guys that are
eligible to have a pool party thrown for
them according to Ricky Morris. So, this
is just so fun just to hear the insights
of what's happening over in that war
room. But, what I really loved about
talking to Ramello is that he literally
dreamt of this moment. And I'm not
talking about making it to the NFL, but
I'm talking about getting drafted here
to the San Francisco 49ers in the Bay
Area. Um he literally had a dream about
this and it was a dream come true. So,
um it wasn't necessarily the San
Francisco 49ers that he was dreaming of,
but he had a dream of the colors red and
gold. And he had a feeling over the
course of a few weeks that it could be
the Colts or it could be the 49ers, but
once he had that dream there was a
little you know,
fairy in his head or a special feeling
in his heart that really got it going to
um teach him that the 49ers are going to
be drafting him and that dream did come
true. And again, a good instinct. Very
good instinct.
>> [laughter]
>> The Holy Spirit was checking in on him.
He got 10 sacks in 2025 and his thing
about getting around big offensive
lineman because a lot of people were
curious about his size is that he quoted
speed and playing chess when he's on
that line of scrimmage. So, he likes to
get into an offensive tackle's mind and
that's how he makes his way into the
pocket and attack that quarterback. Um
so, we don't have a one-on-one with him.
He did speak to the media, but that's no
problem because we we we will catch up
with him during rookie mini camp. But, I
think I know why he was pretty busy. Um
he had a lot of fun at his draft party.
We have a clip from it. Let's roll it
right here. The 49ers SELECT
RAMELLO
>> [cheering]
[cheering]
>> THE POOL PARTIES ARE ALREADY getting
started. Okay, let's move on to third
round pick number 90, running back
Keylon Black. What did you learn about
Black and his collegiate career as he
makes his way to the San Francisco
49ers?
>> Yeah, so he also saw six seasons across
Indiana and James Madison. He had over
2,000 career rushing yards and really
why the 49ers liked him because he is
such a classic Shanahan running back.
He's tough, downhill, and a physical
runner. We love all those things and
he's got a strong character and just
like I said earlier about this draft and
the way that our 49ers front office
drafts is character is such a huge part
of this interview process, such a huge
part of this and he just really clicked
with us, especially Bobby Turner, the
running backs coach and connections with
him is huge cuz he is known for building
real relationships with his running
backs and just like uh Keylon said is
that he loves Bobby and
um Kyle Shanahan and John Lynch said
that
he is
quote unquote Bobby T's type of guy,
which I absolutely love. And Dale
actually got to meet with him at the at
the Senior Bowl and he said, "You can't
help but love the kid and everything he
stands for." That's amazing. Yeah, with
Keylon it was awesome. I talked to Kyle
Shan about him after day three and he
was also talked about during this media
press conference once it was all wrapped
up. And Kyle said that this pick was
very necessary because he's seen
scenarios where a sixth running back is
necessary. That didn't come true
thankfully last season because Christian
McCaffrey was at an all-time high and
was doing amazing during the 2025
campaign, but we've run into situations
where you do need that sixth back.
That's not saying that he's going to be
at the depth chart at number six. We'll
see how, you know, the rest of the off
season plays out in training camp, but
the bodies are absolutely needed at that
position, which is something we'll be
looking forward to tracking as we make
our way to the start of the 2026 season.
Again, true running back. I love his
connection with coach Bobby T, Bobby
Turner. Faithful, if you know Bobby T,
you already know what his antics are
like. He gives written tests to all of
his running back room and he makes them,
you know, do it with a number two pencil
on paper, getting it done. I've talked
to talked to um Kyle Juszczyk about it
even though he's a full back, he's still
in that running back room and he goes,
"Bobby T's intense. You do not play with
that guy." Exactly. And so, it's really
fun to see that uh Keylon and Bobby T
have gone on already. Um he actually
mentioned Bobby T in my one-on-one with
him. So, let's take a look at it right
here.
Faithful, allow me to introduce the
49ers newest running back, Keylon Black.
Keylon, welcome to the team. How would
you describe your running style to the
faithful who are watching you right now?
Yes, just aggressive and aggressive
running style. Attack, attack, attack
always, but also being balanced, being
able to catch the ball out the
backfield, you know, pass protect as
well and run some routes. So, I'm
definitely just excited and excited to
really show what I could do.
What excites you about joining San
Francisco's offense and learning from
someone like Christian McCaffrey?
Man, it's just like the all around the
all around aspect, learning from a coach
like Bobby T and then learning from
Christian McCaffrey, one of the goats in
the game, someone I've looked up to
since the Stanford days. Like finally
just being able to get to this level and
also maintain it and be get become
better is just something I'm looking
forward to.
Finally, Keylon, what does this moment
mean to you personally and who helped
you get to this moment?
It means so much to me. I've been
playing football since I was 4 years old
and I've always dreamt of having my name
called on draft night. Um I honestly
didn't know it was going to come this
soon, but um like God has my steps
ordered and you know, my parents, mom
and dad, fiance, they've all helped me
get to this point and I just really
thank God that I'm that I'm here right
now. Congratulations. We can't wait to
welcome you to the Bay.
Thank you. I really do appreciate it.
We've made it now to the fourth round
pick number 107, defensive lineman
Grayson Halton. What did you learn about
Grayson and what do you love about
Grayson? Yeah, so he stayed with
Oklahoma for all four years and he was a
2025 team captain because he showed that
and he showed his leadership throughout
his four years being there. He had 16
1/2 tackles for loss, 9 1/2 sacks. He
had elite explosiveness for this
position. He had a top vertical out of
all the DTs at the combine. He hit 36
1/2 at the vertical at nearly 300 lb,
which is insane. And really why
the 49ers in the front office really
liked him is cuz he's the type of
D-lineman that the 49ers look for. He's
got leadership, intangibles, and the
burst and the explosiveness is something
that they really look for. Something
that Kyle Shanahan said is quote unquote
extremely explosive, boom, he's off the
ball.
>> [laughter]
>> That's right. That get off speed is
something that he highlighted not only
with the coaching staff, but with me in
the one-on-one, which we'll take a look
at soon. But again, loving the fact that
he's the team captain at Oklahoma, was
there for his entire collegiate career.
Which is cool for him because he's from
San Diego. So, we're bringing him back
over to the West Coast. Welcome back to
California, Grayson. But also, he's a
versatile player. He knows both the
interior and the edge of this D-line and
what I really like that he highlighted
of him having a fast get off speed is
that defensive coach Chris Kosiorek,
he's big on that. That's something
that's the number one thing he looks for
in his draft prospects and so, it's fun
to hear how those connections are
already forming before we actually get
to see them in 49ers practice gear over
at the SAP Performance Facility. So,
check out my one-on-one with Grayson.
Faithful, I'm sitting down with your
newest defensive lineman, Grayson
Halton. Grayson, welcome to the 49ers.
Tell me what this moment feels like.
Uh moment feels so real. Um you know,
um you know, growing up as a kid, you
know, you always watch watch the NFL
draft, but you know, people don't know
the process, you know, that goes in
before before the draft. So, you know,
just to hear my name getting called, you
know, it's a lot of hard work, you know,
a lot of dedication, a lot of
consistency. So, you know, I'm just at
this point ready to get to work, but
definitely, you know, a kid for
fulfilled dream.
Now, tell me, what do you think is the
first thing 49ers fans are going to
notice about your game?
First thing that they're going to notice
is me getting off that rock.
You know, that's my first my first quick
steps and you know, just enthusiastic
how how excited I am to play the game,
you know, after I make a play.
Now, tell me about the people who helped
you in your journey to making it to the
NFL. What would you say to them right
now?
Yeah, I just tell them that I love them,
you know, thank you for everything that
you've done for me, you know, never
giving up, you know, my mom, my dad, you
know, my family around me, my brothers,
sisters,
you know, it's it's it's took a village.
So, you know, I just appreciate them,
you know, love them taking care of me.
Awesome. Welcome to the 49ers family.
Thank you. Sticking in the fourth round,
pick number 127, offensive lineman
Carver Willis. What do you know about
Carver as he makes his way over to San
Francisco?
>> Yeah, so Carver spent six years college
career between Kansas State and
Washington. So, he's just recently
coming out of UDub. Starting uh tackle
who helped cut sacks and boost the run
game. He's kind of a multi-sport
athlete. He actually has a cycling
background. So, you know, endurance,
legs, we love to see that for an
offensive lineman. But, really why the
49ers liked him is his versatility.
He's, you know, a obviously proven
tackle, but also has a great guard
projection for him. He's smart,
experienced, durable and a quote that
Kyle Shanahan said is "We'll start him
off on the inside, give him a chance to
earn that spot." So, that's super fun.
And just a little fun nugget about him,
he actually got into football because
his sister played at O-line and
linebacker. So, kind of cool to see
female kind of influence here. And he I
know he's got a big family and has a few
other sisters as well. Trench play runs
in the family. And his family is
supporting him every single step of the
way. That's one of my favorite moments
during these draft calls I had with each
guy as soon as they got off the real
draft call with John Lynch and Kyle
Shanahan is just getting to see the room
that they're in when they get called
with the environment is like, who
they're surrounded by, and he was
surrounded by a ton of friends and
family. He when I was talking to him,
this was a little bit off camera. We
were just having a conversation.
I go, "Okay, like tell me what your
experience was like being drafted and
realizing your dream of making it to the
NFL." And he goes, "Oh, it was amazing.
My mom's actually sitting here right
next to me." And he panned the camera
over to them. And they were like, "Hi."
We were just cheering. And so, it was
really fun to feel the energy that comes
out of the those rooms. But, we'll get
to that clip very soon. But, about
Carver, he mentioned that Washington's
offense was very similar to the 49ers. I
asked him, "Okay, what similarities are
there? Can you give me some details?"
And he goes, "Everything." Everything
that the 49ers do, they really like them
up in Seattle over at UDub. So, it's
really cool to see how he could probably
be a plug-and-play guy once we get into
rookie mini camp, training camp, and
work our way to the 2026 season. And he
also had a ton of conversations and
workouts with the offensive Chris
Forster. And so, they've already built
and established that relationship. And
so, hopefully that also comes into play
as he's learning what it takes to make
it to the next level and to play in the
NFL. So, as I mentioned that one-on-one
clip, here it goes. Now joining the
49ers offensive line, faithful, please
welcome Carver Willis. Carver, tell me
what that phone call was like with the
49ers front office. What was your
reaction? What was your family's
reaction?
Uh it was it was crazy. Um it was a big
surprise.
Um we're all just kind of sitting here.
We're trying to you know, everyone's
kind of on pins and needles trying to
you know, fill the time and distract
yourself a little bit. And then the
phone rings and everything kind of
stops. So, um certainly a special moment
and one I'm very grateful for. But, I'm
I'm not sure I've quite come down off
that high just yet.
Beautiful. What are some of the
similarities between the Washington
Huskies offense and the 49ers offense
that you've learned? Um everything. Uh
we modeled pretty much everything off
the Niners. We even watched their
practice film to learn how to practice.
We watched their walk-through film to
learn how to walk through.
Um we we UDub loves the 49ers. Anything
the 49ers do is just about as good as
gold up in Seattle. So, yeah, it's it's
uh it's awesome to have that carryover.
Now that you've been drafted, what's
motivating you moving forward?
Uh just the ability to compete, you
know? Um
everyone kind of talks about you know,
where I'm moving on the O-line, where
I'm going. So, I'm excited to go and
learn learn a lot and go compete at what
whatever position I'm at.
Congratulations and welcome to the
family. Thank you so much. I appreciate
[snorts] it, Bree. Our last pick in the
fourth round, pick number 139,
cornerback Ephesians Price. Brooke, what
did you learn about Price?
>> Yeah, so he's a four-year player across
Arizona and Washington. So, another
Husky coming out here. He's a 6'4 long
corner with legit speed. He ran a 4.45,
which is so crazy. I mean, we love to
see corners, but it's really hard not to
notice a 6'4 corner out here. He's got
strong zone instincts and ball
disruption. He got seven pass breakups
in 2025. And really why the 49ers liked
him is not only because he's a 6'4
corner, but his coverage versatility and
his ability to disrupt early on these
plays. Um a quote that John Lynch said,
"The length allows him a lot of
different avenues to contribute, a lot
of versatility." So, I think a common
trend we can see here is a versatility
factor between all these draftees. Um
and you know, position flexibility is
huge. Another theme is consensus.
>> And consensus, yeah.
>> We heard from the scouts actually, the
49ers scouting team, that he has great
size, length, and he's a tough
competitor. Pretty much mirroring
exactly what John Lynch said. So, it was
across the board. This is how they felt
on Ephesians Price. Again, fast,
physical, downfield defender. But, what
I really like getting to know about him
is that he's a true California native.
And he actually has ties with Deommodore
Lenoir. Um I think uh
his brother played with Demo. I can find
that connection again. But, it's really
cool to see how he's making his way back
to California. Check out my one-on-one
with him right here.
Ephesians Price, welcome to the San
Francisco 49ers. How are you feeling
after hearing your name called?
It's just a blessing, man.
I worked so hard for moments like these.
And this is a once-in-a-lifetime
opportunity. So, it's it's a blessing to
be here
with my family celebrating.
Um and yeah.
You're a California native. How does it
feel to come back to your home state?
And what do you already know about the
49ers organization?
Man, um
First of all, it feels great. It's
amazing. Um
just to hear my name called by the
49ers. Um I'm from Southern California.
Like, that's I don't have a favorite
team, but a lot of my family's team is
the 49ers.
Uh so, it's great. Um just a blessing.
Uh
And what I know about the 49ers is they
they like um
long, fast corners that can do it all.
And that's you, right? Mhm. Yes, ma'am.
Awesome to hear. Now, you also earned
Washington's Defensive Skill Player of
the Year award. Tell me, how do you
define your style of play?
Um like I said, a long long fast guy
that is very versatile. Um
physical in press man coverage. Um love
to play zone uh
to get turnovers to get the ball back to
the QB. Thank you so much, Ephesians.
Can't wait to welcome you to the Bay.
Thank you. Now moving on to the final
round that the 49ers made selections in,
and that's the fifth round, pick number
154, linebacker Jayden Dugger. Brooke,
what stands out about Jayden? I mean,
Jayden is a phenomenal player. I'm
looking at the stats. But, just a little
background about him, he came from
Georgetown and then to Louisiana. He was
a former safety turned linebacker. And
just in his 2025 season, he had 125
tackles, 13 tackles for loss, and four
sacks. I had to double-check on that
when I was initially writing the article
because I was like, "Oh, that was his
overall stats, right?" No, just his 2025
season, which is absolutely insane. So,
it's really hard not to like a guy like
that with stats like that. But, another
reason why a few other reasons why they
liked him, so he has a hybrid skill set,
coverage and tackling. His size and
length, he's 6'4 and has a 7-ft
wingspan, which is wild. And he's got a
huge developmental upside. So, lots of
things to like about him. But, Bree, you
got to talk to him one-on-one. What did
you learn from him? Yeah, uh one quick
thing I feel like Fred Warner knows a
thing or two about moving from the
backfield into linebacker. So, we'll see
how he can translate some of that
experience over to Jayden. Um but, one
other piece that I liked is that Matt
Barrows called it out and John Lynch
picked up on it. Uh Matt Barrows, he's a
beat writer over here with the 49ers.
But, linebackers coach K.J. Wright, he's
also a Pro Bowl player, former Super
Bowl champion. He has very similar
measurables to Jayden, similar weight,
similar height, similar wingspan. And
so, Lynch saw this and he called out
K.J. and said, "Hey, I think you're
drafting yourself here."
>> [laughter]
>> And so, they put up their measurables in
the war room and were comparing K.J. and
Jayden and seeing what their
similarities were like. So, that was a
fun tidbit to learn about Jayden. So,
let's check out the one-on-one I had
with him right here. From Louisiana to
the Bay, faithful, please welcome
linebacker Jayden Dugger. Jayden, how
are you feeling right now?
I'm feeling blessed. I mean, I dreamed
of this since I was a kid. So, just
finally being here in this situation, it
doesn't feel real right now. So, I'm
trying to take it all in. But, I'm
extremely blessed.
You led your team with 125
tackles in the 2025 season. What are you
most proud of from your collegiate
career?
I think my how much I was adaptable in
any situation I was put in. I mean, I
went through a lot through my career.
And then
just being able to still perform and not
making any excuses for myself is
probably
what I'm most proud of for myself.
And now you've made it to the league.
What message do you have for all the
49ers fans watching you right now?
I'm just ready to come in and work and
then help the team win whatever way I
can, whether that's special teams,
defense, whatever the coaches ask me to
I'm willing to do it. So, I'm excited.
Amazing. Congratulations, Jayden.
Welcome to the family.
Thank you. Now the final pick of the
49ers 2026 NFL draft, it came at pick
number 179, offensive lineman Enrique
Cruz Jr. He goes by Kiko. Brooke, what
stands out about his career as he makes
his way over to the 49ers?
>> Well, I love it. Kiko was a five-year
player from Syracuse and then ended his
career in Kansas as a full-time starter.
He earned all-Big 12 honorable mention.
And really why the 49ers liked him was
because his length and power combo and
basically his overall package was just
really elite traits for an O-line um
offensive lineman. He has developmental
tackle and guard flexibility. And at the
NFL combine, Cruz Jr. showcased his
outstanding length, standing at 6'5 and
313 lbs. So, he's got a really big NFL
frame that we love. And John Lynch said
this about him, "It speaks to the type
of athlete he is. We think he may have a
guard flex." So, we love to see that, a
lot of traits. But, what did you learn
from him? Yeah, the first thing he told
his family when he realized that he was
going over to San Francisco to play with
the 49ers, he goes, "Do y'all realize
I'm going to learn from Trent Williams,
a future Hall of Famer?" That's the
first thing he told his family about how
excited he was to come to the 49ers. And
yeah, I'm about to show the clip here
about my one-on-one with him and a
little bit of how excited he is to come
play for the 49ers, but a little bit of
context before we go into this video. We
were chit-chatting before we were on the
record. We talked a lot about his
grandma who he called his role model.
She is a two-time breast cancer survivor
and they have a really special
connection. She's again one of the first
people that he talked to right after
getting the call and he had a ton of
family support. We bonded a ton over
culture as me being Nicaraguan say and
Mexican and him being full Puerto Rican.
He was so proud to have that Latino fan
base and family over here in the Bay
Area that can cheer him on during his
rookie season. So, check out my
one-on-one with him right here.
Now joining the San Francisco 49ers
offensive line, this is Enrique Cruz Jr.
Enrique, how are you spending your draft
day?
I'm I'm right here with all my family.
I'm We're at a restaurant right now.
I've got 100 family members celebrating
with me and it's just so amazing. I'm so
happy to be. Amazing. Congratulations.
Now, you've shared that your grandma is
your biggest role model. How must she be
feeling right now?
Oh my me and my grandma we used to be so
emotional after the phone call. We're
both crying and we're just We're just so
happy. She's She's so happy for me right
now.
I absolutely love to hear it. Now, your
familiar Latina is here in the Bay Area.
What message do you have for the Latino
community and all the 49ers fans out
here?
Let's do this. Let's go. Let's do this.
I'm so happy to be in the Bay Area.
Let's go. Love you guys. Let's get it.
Welcome to the 49ers family. Enjoy your
day.
Thank you. Thank you so much. What a fun
list to run through. I mean, we got to
learn a little bit of their background,
a little bit of their stats, but we're
only going to get to learn a little bit
more come rookie mini camp when they're
all here. We get to actually speak to
them, get more content with them and get
to learn more about them, but I think
overall a really successful 2026 NFL
draft. All right, faithful. Thank you so
much for tuning into this episode of the
saloon as we ran through every single
pick made by the San Francisco 49ers in
the 2026 NFL draft. This was another
successful draft in the books. So,
faithful, stay tuned, subscribe to the
saloon on YouTube, SiriusXM and all your
favorite podcast platforms because you
don't want to miss a thing as we make
our way to the 2026 season. That'll do
it for today and go Niners. [music]
>> [music]